Guide to the Dwight Hall, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Dwight Hall, Yale University, photographs
1846-1937
RU 610
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.25
The collection contains photographs of Dwight Hall at Yale, which was known as the Old Library from 1889 to 1930. Included are interior and exterior views and views of the building taken during the various stages of the construction or demolition of the surrounding structures.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains photographs of Dwight Hall at Yale, which was known as the Old Library from 1889 to 1930. Included are interior and exterior views and views of the building taken during the various stages of the construction or demolition of the surrounding structures.
College buildings -- Design and construction; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings
- Photographs, Series I
  - General views
    - circa 1846, etchings (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - circa 1860s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - circa 1862 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - circa 1865 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - pre-1888 [1867? Earliest date advertised on back of Notman card; all the same photograph with differently cropped enlargements] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Pre-1888 [1871?] (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - circa 1881, rear view (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Pre-1888 [1884?] (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - pre-1888 [1888 before Kent Dome] (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - pre-1888, before construction of Kent Chemistry Laboratory (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1888-1890, after construction of Kent Chemistry Laboratory, background before removal of Philosophical Building (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1888-1896, after construction of Kent Chemistry Laboratory, 1888, and before Woolsey Statue, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - pre-1890, before removal of Philosophical Building (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - pre-1890 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - post-1890, following construction of Kent and Chittenden (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1896-1906, after Woolsey Statue, before Linsly Hall (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - post-1907, after addition of a floor to Kent Hall (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1907-1925, with Linsly & Chittenden, before McClellan, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - post-1931, after removal of books to Sterling Library (1930) and renovation of the building (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - post-1932, after construction of Jonathan Edwards College (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - circa 1937 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Interior views
    - circa 1869, Nave (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - post-1879, Nave (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - pre-1931, Nave (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - post-1932, Nave (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Interiors other than Nave (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Oversize (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Slides (Box 4)
  - Transparencies (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Folio
    - Exteriors
      - From southwest (Box DR22F73)
      - Front (Box DR22F73)
      - Signed etching (Box DR22F73)
    - Interiors
      - Nave (Box DR22F74)
      - Biblical room (Box DR22F74)
      - Reading room (Box DR22F74)
      - Linonia & Brothers Room (Box DR22F74)
      - Circulation (Box DR22F74)
      - Second floor stacks (Box DR22F74)
      - Newspaper and periodical reading room (Box DR22F74)